MEGAN MCDEVITT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

mcdevittbass@gmail.com

mcdevittbass.github.io/portfolio

415-816-6973

♀ Greater Buffalo Area (open to move)

in megmcd

mcdevittbass

Whether I'm developing my double bass or JavaScript skills, I'm always striving to improve. In my 10-year career as a musician and teacher, I have developed the arts of attention to detail, long-term planning, and discipline through self-awareness, creativity, and curiosity.

I am now applying these attributes to the tech world after completing Nucamp's Full Stack Bootcamp with honors. When I'm not building a React app, learning Python, or playing music, you can find me hanging out with my husband and my dog, Ligeti.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, C, Python

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, ReactNative, Redux, NodeJS, React Hooks **TOOLS & DATABASES:** Git/Github, Bash, MongoDB, Max/MSP

Education

Nucamp Full Stack Bootcamp Jan. 2020 to June 2020

Certificate with Honors

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Redux, React Native, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB

University of Michigan DMA Music 2017 Aug. 2014 to Aug. 2017

San Francisco Conservatory of Music Masters Music 2010 Aug. 2008 to May 2010

University of California, Sept. 2003 to Santa Cruz June 2007 Bachelors Music 2007

Awards

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp · June
Certificate of Honor 2020
Completed 5-month coding bootcamp with honors.

Projects

Full Stack Developer - Neutral Zone App (pair)

Making an interactive app for an online version of restorative circles for a teen center.

- Regularly meet with client to discuss specifications and progress
- · Use React to make a responsive, interactive user interface
- · Make decisions on how to incorporate backend
- Consult with partner to determine best priorities, debug, and decide on frameworks

Tech Stack: React (Javascript), Konva library, backend TBD

Game Developer - Intergalactic Trash Collector (solo)

Game made using Phaser JS as part of Mintbean's Hackathon.

• Wrote code in JavaScript to create background, sprites, and responses to keyboard input.

- Troubleshot conflicting information from confusing documentation.
- Deployed using Github pages.

Tech Stack: JS, HTML, Phaser 3 library

Front End Developer - Five Points Bakery Site (Solo)

Feb. 2020 to Current

Aug. 2020 to Current

Aug. 2020 to Current

New-and-improved website for a Buffalo bakery including modals, forms, carousels, and a beautiful layout. Then, code was refactored from HTML site to React/S, creating reusable components to display all of the same features.

- · Met with Five Points owners to asses specifications to give them the results they wanted, then followed up.
- Designed and implemented most of the site pages and features in an elegant layout.
- Fixed bug in the navigation bar I struggled with centering the navigation bar, until I sought out a better
 understanding of flex boxes and Bootstrap's use of them. I fixed the centering issue by keeping nav-items
 consistent sizes via flex-grow and flex-basis.
- Updated the site to React to maximize efficiency and speed.
- Deployed to Github Pages to show client the product in progress.

Tech Stack: React, SCSS (originally HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery)

Contributor - evolution (open source)

July 2020 to Aug. 2020

Open-ended project within a Junior Developer community.

- Refactored components from html to React and added some styling.
 - Submitted a pull request on GitHub.
- Responded to comments quickly and updated code based on specifications.

Tech Stack: HTML, JS, React

Front End Developer - Portfolio Site (solo)

May 2020 to June 2020

Professional portfolio site to display my projects and information.

- Assessed goals for the project to ensure clarity of development and production.
- Created clean design using Reactstrap for optimal readability and ease of use.
- Updated class components to use React Hooks to stay abreast of the latest technological developments.

Tech Stack: React, SCSS, Bootstrap

Employment

Megan McDevitt Consulting

Software Developer

Buffalo, NY Feb. 2020 to Current

• Design professional quality websites and web apps for local businesses.

- Meet with stakeholders to establish vision & build a prioritized list of features
- · Write efficient code and deploy it.
- Meet with stakeholders regularly to review and incorporate feedback.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React (with Redux and Hooks), React Native, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Git/GitHub

Buffalo String Works

Associate Directo

Buffalo, NY Jan. 2018 to July 2020

Sept. 2017 to Jan. 2018

• Managed year-round program planning to ensure processes for efficient/effective operations.

- Managed all program data through Airtable bases, ensuring organized, efficient retrieval of information.
- Designed, created, and distributed monthly newsletters to broader Buffalo String Works community, maintaining brand consistency, to secure donor and community engagement.
- · Communicated daily with parents from under-resourced communities, particularly refugee groups.

Site Manager

• Assured safety and preparation for program of over 50 students.

Assured safety and preparation for program of over 30 students

Artist Teacher Sept. 2017 to June 2020

Planned curriculum and taught double bass in groups to students from 4th through 10th grade, giving them mentorship, new skills, and a sense of belonging.

Megan McDevitt, Professional Musician Double Bass Instructor

San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo June 2011 to Aug. 2019

Planned curriculum, prepared performances, and regularly maintained double bass studios of 4-15 students of middle school and high school age, providing mentorship and new skills, and clear communication with parents.

San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo Sept. 2011 to Current

er

Prepare, rehearse, and perform in many orchestras, chamber groups, new music ensembles, and solo recitals, most recently with the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra.